# Kendra Kwoka

Austin, Texas, 78727 Phone: 936.520.3642

Email: kendrakwoka@gmail.com

**Portfolio:** https://ancient-castle-12194.herokuapp.com/

Github: https://github.com/kkwoka

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-kwoka-553b68196/

### **Summary**

Full Stack Web Developer with experience building responsive and progressive web applications for today's market. A passionate, hard-worker and lifelong learner, always expanding knowledge and skills with the latest trends and technologies available. Experienced team player equipped with the technical know-how and personal drive necessary to get every job done efficiently and precisely. Equipped with skills needed to create products that enrich the lives of users.

### **Technical Skills**

**Technologies:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Popper.js / Tippy.js, Local Storage, Session Storage, APIs, VUE.js, Material-ui

**Quality and Performance:** Unit Testing, Google Lighthouse, Webpack, PWAs (Progressive Web Apps), Lazy Loading, Service Workers

**Server-Side Development:** User Authentication, Sequelize, Mongoose, MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js)

Databases: MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, IndexedDB

Deployment: Heroku, Git

### Education

Bootcamp Certificate (Full Stack): Trilogy Education Services / University of Texas - Austin // Grade: A+

A 24-week, Full Stack, intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Science, Speech Language Pathology: University of Texas - Austin // GPA: 3.74

## **Projects**

#### A La Board

https://github.com/kkwoka/A La Board | https://warm-bayou-44198.herokuapp.com/

- An app for board game enthusiasts to find new games that interest them and save them to their account. Users can then narrow down their saved board games by multiple options (explayer size, max play time) to pick the perfect board game to play with any party group.
- Core Responsibilities:
  - o MySQL GET requests from database && POST requests to database
  - o Created all pages except 'hotitems' page
  - o All page layouts (except hotitems) and UI styling / polishing via Material-ui.
- Tools / Languages: MySQL / JawsDB, React.js, JavaScript, Material-ui, Boardgamegeek API

https://github.com/kkwoka/C-19 | https://secret-spire-45995.herokuapp.com/

- A COVID-19 patient portal, easily accessed by physicians nationwide, for storing patient information to ensure accurate tracking and reporting of tested patients.
- Core Responsibilities:
  - o Set up local and heroku databases for patient information storage.
  - o Created 'Add' and 'Delete' database manipulation routes
  - o Created all page url routings
- Tools / Languages: MySQL / JawsDB, Vue.js, JavaScript

### Smorgas-Chord

https://github.com/kkwoka/Smorgas-Chord | https://kkwoka.github.io/Smorgas-Chord/

- Allows the user to search lyrics and guitar tabs for popular songs using two different API. The lyrics will appear on the page while the guitar tabs will open into a separate Songsterr page. The previously searched songs will appear in the history as clickable links, should the user want to look through their search history and pull up song and lyric information from previous searches.
- Core Responsibilities:
  - o All JavaScript code: Connecting to & displaying both Lyrics and Tabs API based on user input, user input's history storage
- Tools / Languages: JavaScript / jQuery, APIs (Happi.dev, Songsterr, Kanye.rest), AJAX, Bulma CSS, Tippy.js

### **Professional Work Experience**

**Bouldin Creek Cafe**, Austin, Texas — Server

(November 2019 - Current)

Waited 6-12 tables (18-70 people) at any given time. Responsible for ensuring great customer experience while meticulously caring for individual allergies / medical conditions / dietary restrictions. Required meticulous eye for detail and gathering information.

**Ludington Bay Brewing Co.,** Ludington, Michigan — Bartender / Server

(April 2019 - October 2019)

Tended bar with 1-100 occupants at a time. Learned about brewing and canning processes of beer. Hosted, tended bar, and served for events in the 'landing room' with 10-30 people. Required consistent and positive team work in high-traffic and hectic times.

REI, Austin, Texas — Sales Lead, SIF

(July 2016 - November 2018)

Due to strong leadership and interpersonal communication skills, worked closely with Store Management, Visual Lead, and Sales Leads to identify and resolve customer and employee issues. By performing unique transactions: special orders, class registration, special ticket sales, store mail-outs, customer service skills significantly sharpened.

**Peached Tortilla,** Austin, Texas— Asst. Operations Mngr; Warehouse Mngr; Food Truck Mngr (August 2015 - July 2016)

Showcased attention to detail, decision making, and organizational skills by creating a new scheduling system which resolved previous scheduling issues. Organizational, time management, and leadership skills significantly strengthened by working concurrently as Shift Lead, Food Truck Manager, Warehouse Manager, and Asst. Operations Manager.